我是奧利弗•奎恩
My name is Oliver Queen.
五年裡  我被困在地獄一般的小島上
After five years on a hellish island,
我回來只有一個目標
I have come home with only one goal--
拯救我的城市
To save my city.
但要達到目標  我不能像過去一樣成為兇手
But to do so, I can't be the killer I once was.
為了紀念我的朋友  我只能偽裝成另一個人
To honor my friend's memory, I must be someone else.
成為另一個存在
I must be something else.
《綠箭》前情回顧
Previously on "Arrow"...
斯萊德
Slade!
我需要一個有能力修船的人
I need someone qualified to fix this boat.
我希望亨德里克先生跟你在一起
I sure hope a Mr. Hendrik is there with you.
我死也不會回去的
There's no way in hell I'm going back there.
拜託  把槍放下
Please, put the gun down!
在你瞭解什麼叫徹底絕望前
You cannot die until you have known
我不會讓你死的
complete despair.
你會瞭解的  我向你承諾
And you will, I promise.
遠離西婭
Stay away from Thea.
不  我做不到
No...I can't!
她在你身邊的時候非常不安全  你愛她
She's not safe when she's around you. You love her,
所以你要按我說的做
and that's why you're going to do what I'm asking.
這是個危險的城市
It's a dangerous city.
威爾遜先生
Mr. Wilson?
叫我斯萊德就行
Call me Slade.
你的睫毛膏花了
Your mascara is running.
謝謝
Thank you.
你沒事吧
Are you all right?
我不知道
I don't know.
是我的男友
It's my boyfriend.
現在是前男友了
Ex-boyfriend now.
他突然決定和我分手
He just completely out of nowhere decides to end things.
我太瞭解心碎這回事了
Heartbreak is something I know all too well.
一旦心碎很難恢復的
It's not an easy thing to recover from.
有時永遠都好不了
Sometimes you never do.
我們不是在...
Um, we're not at--
這不是我家
This isn't my home.
你不回家  西婭
You're not going home, Thea.
下車
Get out.
Get out!
你好  西婭
Hello, Thea.
見到你真高興
It's a pleasure to meet you.
綠   箭   俠
第二季 第十八集
星城哨兵
沒時間了
No time.
今年  你放那些壞人一條生路
You letting the bad guys stay alive this year
後果就是監獄都已經滿員了
has filled the jails up to capacity.
是啊
Yeah.
準備好了嗎
Ready?
我一直在和莎拉練習
Well, I've been working with Sara,
但我沒天賦
but I'm not exactly a natural.
我也沒有
Neither was I.
好吧  我們要忙活了
Ok. We have some work to do.
抱歉  我今天
Sorry, I'm just having a
很難專注於我們要幹的事
hard time keeping my head in the game today.
因為西婭
Thea?
我一直在想
I just can't stop thinking
如果我告訴她真相  最糟糕的後果會是什麼
what's the worst that can happen if I just told her the truth?
我告訴了一個人真相  而他被閃電擊中了
Well, I told a guy the truth and he got struck by lightning.
說句公道話
To be fair,
從統計學角度來看  也許不會再發生了
probably won't happen again, statistically.
告訴西婭真相不會讓她更安全
Telling Thea the truth won't make her safer.
反而恰恰相反
Just the opposite.
羅伊  我們做的事很危險
What we're doing, Roy, it's dangerous.
任何在我們身邊的人都可能受傷
And anyone that is even in our orbit can get hurt.
再試試
Try again.
這次
This time...
瞄準了
Aim.
那是什麼
What are those?
奎恩企業一個月的手機短信
About a month's worth of phone messages from Queen Consolidated.
扔了
Toss them.
上個月的手機短信我也扔了
That's what I did with last month's phone messages.
斯萊德還逍遙法外  我沒空管公司的事
With Slade out there, I don't have time for the company.
你得騰出時間  奧利弗
Well, you have to make time, Oliver.
至少三小時
At least three hours.
年度董事會
The annual board meeting.
總裁不可能不出席的
There's absolutely zero way that the CEO can avoid being there.
我知道有一陣子了
And I know it's been a while,
所以別忘了  總裁是你
so in case you've forgotten, that's you.
你記得把西裝放哪兒了嗎
Do you remember where you put your business suit?
或者你把西裝也放在很酷的玻璃盒裡了
Or do you keep it in a cool glass case, too?
我要把你們都殺了
I'm going to kill all of you!
這不是私人恩怨
This is not personal.
也許有點吧
Well, maybe a little.
不是
It's not.
這是為了生存
This is about survival.
生存  這樣說謀殺真好聽啊
Survival. What a noble word for murder.
斯萊德讓我們別無選擇
Slade gave us no option.
亨德里克換奧利弗
Hendrik for Oliver.
我們有什麼權力決定
And what gives any of us the right to decide
誰的生命更有價值
one's life is more valuable than another?
他被綁起來了  我們沒有
He is tied up. We are not.
一旦他修好了船
Once he gets the boat working,
斯萊德就不需要他了
Slade will have no more need for him.
我們別自欺欺人了
So let's not kid ourselves.
這樣做就等於判了亨德里克的死刑
Doing this is effectively sentencing Hendrik to death.
換做我們其中任何人  他也會這樣做的
He would do the same thing to any of us!
毫不猶豫地這樣做
In heartbeat!
這是唯一的選擇
This is only option.
如果還有機會呢
What if it's also an opportunity?
什麼機會
To do what?
殺斯萊德的機會
To kill Slade.
我知道我有一陣子沒來了
I know that I haven't been here in a while,
但你看起來不像是整個董事會成員吧
but you don't look like the entire board of directors.
會議半小時後才開始
The meeting doesn't start for another half hour.
真的嗎
Really?
我照例把所有預約的時間提前了30分鐘
I routinely bump all appointments 30 minutes
考慮到你經常遲到
in anticipation of you being late.
這辦法不錯
It's good policy.
但謝謝你為此不再冬眠了
But, thank you for coming out of hibernation for this.
不管你有沒有意識到  大樓上是你的名字
Whether you recognize it or not, it's your name on the building,
不管你缺席多少次會議
and no matter how many meetings you miss,
你依舊是公司的代言人
you're still the public face of this company.
伊莎貝爾  我知道最近無暇顧及公司
Isabel, I realize I have been distracted.
謝謝你幫我收拾爛攤子
Thank you for picking up the slack.
雖然我們是非傳統的合夥人
Ours is an unconventional partnership,
但也是合夥人
but it's a partnership.
而且很有效
And it's working.
的確是
Indeed it is.
奧利弗
Oliver...
你母親來了
Your mother's here.
家庭矛盾嗎
Family squabble?
羅切夫女士最近怎麼樣
And how is Ms. Rochev these days?
還在因為自己家人的事生氣嗎
Still angry that Dorothy dropped a house on her sister?
你來幹什麼
What are you doing here?
-你跟西婭聯繫過嗎  -沒有
- Have you heard from Thea? - No.
你沒有回我電話
You haven't returned any of my phone calls,
所以我沒有辦法只能當面找你
so I'm left to resort to checking in person
問你參不參加今晚的辯論會
as to whether you're attending the debate tonight.
我說過我在公開場合會支援你競選的
I told you that I would publicly support your campaign.
還有事嗎
Anything else?
如果你今晚都不能有個好兒子的樣子
It would be embarrassing for us both
那我們倆都會很尷尬的
if you couldn't at least appear to be my son tonight.
我很擅長偽裝成別的樣子
I have gotten pretty good at pretending to be someone I'm not.
我跟你學的
I learned it from you.
打擾了  你看見西婭•奎恩了嗎
Oh, excuse me, have you seen Thea Queen?
好吧
OK.
閃電妞  我是奧利  我在辯論會這裡
Speedy, it's Ollie, and I'm at the debate,
我以為你也在呢
where I thought you would be.
我知道羅伊的事你很生氣
Listen, I know that you're upset about Roy,
但媽媽需要我們兩個都來
but mom needs both of us here.
所以拜託了  回我電話
So please, just call me back.
你看起來不是很開心  一切還好嗎
You do not look happy. Is everything all right?
是的  我的妹妹有點遲到了
Yes. My sister's just a little late.
我想這可能是因為我
I'm afraid that's my fault.
星城警局堅持車隊開到讓我過來
SCPD insisted that I arrive with a motorcade.
這阻礙了全市的交通
We tied up traffic all over the city.
西婭肯定是被堵在路上了
I'm sure Thea's probably just fallen victim to gridlock.
我再給她打個電話試試
Well, I should probably try her again.
祝你今晚好運  塞巴斯蒂安
Good luck tonight, Sebastian.
謝謝
Thank you, sir.
我以為後臺是閒人勿進的
I thought backstage was supposed to be restricted access.
我想這就是做地區檢察官的好處吧
The benefits of having a district attorney's badge, I guess.
你來祝莫伊拉好運嗎
You stop by to wish Moira good luck?
是的  但我很高興碰到了你
I did. But I'm really glad I ran into you.
我應該向你道歉
I owe you an apology.
我曾指責你做了很多糟糕的事
I accused you of really terrible things.
你當時正處在一個非常艱難的時期
You were going through a very difficult time.
我很高興你慢慢恢復了
I'm just happy you're on the mend.
祝你今晚好運
Good luck tonight.
今晚需要運氣的可不是我
I'm not the one who's going to need it.
塞巴斯蒂安•布拉德不是你們想的那樣
Sebastian Blood is not the man you think he is.
他不會通過社會服務使城市復興
He's not going to revive the city with social services.
星城市長競選辯論
2014年度競選
沒有資金支持的委任會讓城市破產
He's going to bankrupt it with unfunded mandates.
奎恩女士對我競選的不滿是
Mrs. Queen's problem with my proposals
這一切都由那1%的富人買單
is that they will be paid for by the one percent.
是時候讓富人們
It's time that the wealthiest
擔起自己的責任了
people stop avoiding their responsibility.
但這會限制他們選人用人的能力
But it will limit their abilities to hire people.
好了  時間到  我提醒候選人
All right, that's time, and I will remind the candidates
請不要再打斷對方
to please refrain from interrupting.
接下來是下一位星城選民
Now we have the next in our series of video questions
通過視頻提出的問題
submitted by Starling City voters.
來自...西婭•奎恩
This one comes from... Thea Queen.
一定是出錯了
Ok, there must be some mistake.
救命
Help!
救命  來人救救我  拜託
Help! Somebody help me, please!
他  斯萊...
He--sla--
天啊
Oh, my God!
西婭•奎恩的生命對你來說值多少錢
我們會找到她的  羅伊  我們會救她回來的
We're going to find her, Roy. We're going to get her back.
她是個堅強的女孩
She's a tough girl.
我們找到她的時候她還會活著嗎
Is she going to be alive when we find her?
你不能這麼想
You can't think like that.
我沒辦法不這麼想
I can't stop thinking like that.
狄格爾先生
Mr. Diggle.
Mr. Diggle!
我好像有發現  正在查
I think I might have found something. I'm working on it.
我暫停競選  貢獻一切資源
I am suspending my campaign and devoting its resources
西婭•奎恩遭綁架
希望西婭•奎恩能安全回來
to the safe return of Thea Queen.
今天  是我們...
Today, the day we both...
視頻上提到了要求  但沒提到贖金
Well, the video referenced a demand, but no ransom,
所以說這可能不是錢的事
which means this might not be about money.
我們會救她回來的  莫伊拉
We're going to get her back, Moira.
我向你保證  西婭會回家的
I promise you. Thea's coming home.
你想想有沒有人
Now, can you think of anyone
會想通過西婭來威脅你
who might want to get to you through Thea?
去年死去的那503個人的家屬都有可能
No one except for the families of the 503 people that died last year.
這跟地震沒有關係
This isn't about the quake.
你怎麼能確定
Well, how can you be so sure?
你們只需要找到那個戴面具的人
You just need to find the man in the mask!
我們在找
Look, we're working on it.
我們在追蹤每一條線索
We're running down every lead.
什麼線索
What are those leads?
天啊
Oh, God!
天啊  我怎麼會讓這種事發生
Oh, God, how could I have let this happen?
失陪一下
Excuse me for a minute.
如果再讓我知道有一個
If I hear about one more
有攻擊性的媒體調查傳送到奎恩先生
invasive press inquiry being sent to Mr. Queen
或者奎恩家的任何家庭成員面前
or to any member of the Queen family,
我就唯你是問
I will hold you personally responsible.
你這樣很嚇人啊  謝謝你
You're very scary. Thank you.
我的工作是幫你處理事務  今天尤甚
My job is to take things off your plate, now more than ever.
說到這個  你還記得在今天董事會上
To that end, you remember how at today's meeting,
董事成員提名的新管理人員嗎
the board nominated new officers?
投票需要在24小時之內進行
Voting has to take place within 24 hours.
美國證監會在看著呢  不能耽擱
It cannot be suspended. It's an SEC thing.
我現在沒心思想這個
I can't think about this right now.
我明白  我很遺憾  但是你必須要想
I know, and I'm sorry, but you have to.
你是公司的總裁  你有責任...
You're the CEO and you have responsibilities--
一直都是你替我負責的
Which you handle for me all the time.
董事會投票與替你出席會議
A board vote is several orders of magnitude, different
是完全不同的
from covering a missed meeting.
你可以臨時任命一位總裁
You could appoint someone CEO pro tempore.
不過那不是個好主意
That's not a good idea.
我現在就任命你
I'm appointing you.
什麼
What?
恭喜你
Congratulations.
你現在是臨時總裁
You are the temporary CEO.
不行
I can't.
求你了
Please.
謝謝
Thank you.
等西婭安全回家了  讓她謝謝我
Have Thea thank me, when she's back safe at home.
奎恩先生  我需要和你談談威爾遜的事
Mr. Queen? I need to talk to you, it's about Mr. Wilson.
西婭最後被看見是在威登酒吧
Since the last place Thea was seen was Verdant,
我通過信用卡記錄列出了昨晚客人的名單
I used credit card receipts, compiled a list of customers last night,
追蹤了他們的電話  黑進去看了他們的照片
pinged all their cell phones and hacked into their photos.
美國國家安全局是對的
The NSA is right;
不用申請批準確實方便多了
it's a lot easier when you don't need a warrant.
我瀏覽了所有照片
I eyeballed every photo.
那得有幾千張照片
There must have been thousands.
為了西婭  我找到了這個
It's Thea. I found this.
在離酒吧三個街區處發現的部分車牌
Partial plate three blocks from the club.
車子是在斯萊德•威爾遜名下的
Car's registered to a Slade Wilson,
車裡有定位導航系統
and it has GPS.
現在車在哪裡
Where is it right now?
停在羅斯福街的一間倒閉的酒吧外
Parked outside a defunct bar on Roosevelt.
你不覺得這樣太容易了嗎
Ok, this doesn't seem easy to you?
斯萊德在自己的名下注冊了一輛車
Slade using a car registered in his name?
整件事都很詭異
The whole thing smells rotten.
無論是西婭還是他在那裡
Either Thea's there or he is.
我們都得去看看
Either way, we have to go.
我就知道你會這麼說
Yeah, I figured you'd say that,
所以我已經提煉好了這個
which is why I worked up these.
西藏蝮蛇毒
Tibetan pit viper venom.
刺客聯盟的人一直用它
The league of assassins' poison of choice.
是我用過的最有效的鎮定劑
And the most powerful sedative that I've ever worked with.
那會給我們帶來優勢
That'll give us an advantage.
而你是我們的另一個優勢
But you are going to give us another.
你確定要我跟著去嗎
Are you sure you want me to go?
你憤怒嗎  利用你的憤怒吧
Are you angry? Use that rage.
你一直都讓我隱忍行事
Well, you're just always telling me to hold back.
今晚不用
Not tonight.
炸彈嗎
Landmines?
這個島是個什麼地方啊
What kind of island is this?
你會拆彈嗎
Can you remove the explosive?
當然會
Certainly.
能不能在不引爆的情況下拆除
Without it going off, eh.
就不那麼確定了
Less certain.
克格勃  我在那學到很多很多東西
Ah, KGB. You taught me many, many things.
無論俄國炸彈
Russian bomb,
還是日本炸彈
Japanese bomb;
它們都會...嘭
they both go...boom.
恭喜  我們還活著  現在要怎麼做
Congratulations, we are not dead. Now what?
我們按照約定讓斯萊德帶走亨德里克
Well, Slade takes Hendrik as we agreed.
等他們走得夠遠的時候...
And then once they're far enough away...
怎麼
What--
你想把炸彈放到亨德里克身上
You want to rig Hendrik into bomb?
彼得說得沒錯  把亨德里克交給斯萊德
Well, Peter was right. Handing Hendrik over to Slade
就等於殺了他  你說得也沒錯
is the same thing as killing him. And you're right, too.
我們別無選擇  不過  這樣至少
We don't have a choice. I mean, at least this way,
可以把斯萊德除掉
he can take out Slade,
那樣我們就可以登船了
and then we can take the ship.
怎麼了
What?
只是  好奇
Just...wondering.
你什麼時候變得如此可怕了
When did you become so scary?
她在哪裡  斯萊德
Where is she, Slade?
他在問你問題
The man asked you a question.
她在哪裡
Where is she?
你要把我怎麼樣  小子  殺了我嗎
What are you going to do, kid? Kill me?
那樣的話誰會告訴你
But then who would tell you...
你親愛的妹妹在什麼地方
where your beloved Thea is?
打電話給蘭斯警探
Call detective Lance.
叫他來這裡
Tell him to come down here.
什麼  為什麼
Wh--what? Why?
來逮捕斯萊德•威爾遜
To arrest Slade Wilson.
你知道這個混蛋為什麼抓西婭•奎恩嗎
Any idea what this son of a bitch wants with Thea Queen?
不知道  我們只需要
No. We just need to make
讓斯萊德說出他把西婭關在哪裡就行
sure that Slade gives up where he's holding her.
奧利弗知道嗎
Does Oliver know?
這件事是你跟綠箭一起行動的
That you're working with the Arrow on this?
綠箭的事奧利弗什麼都不知道
Oliver doesn't know anything about the Arrow.
你還好嗎
Hey, are you OK?
我沒事  就是莫伊拉現在的眼神
Yeah. It's just that look in Moira's eyes
害怕已經失去女兒的那種眼神
terrified she's lost her daughter.
那種感覺我無法承受第二次了  莎拉
I couldn't go through that again, Sara.
蘭斯警官
Officer Lance?
奎恩家的人到了
The Queen family's here.
蘭斯先生  他告訴你西婭在哪了嗎
Mr. Lance, did he tell you where Thea is?
奎恩夫人  謝謝你過來
Mrs. Queen, thank you for coming.
這實在是講不通
This doesn't make any sense.
斯萊德•威爾遜是我們的朋友
Slade Wilson is a friend.
而且他過去的72小時都在哥斯達黎加
And he's been in Costa Rica for the past 72 hours.
他有乘客名單證明  通話記錄
He can provide flight manifests, phone records,
甚至還有錄影證明
even some videos,
所以不可能是他抓了您女兒
so he couldn't have taken your daughter.
如果不是他  為什麼要把他抓來
If he didn't, then why did you arrest him?
不是我們抓的  是治安維持者把他抓住的
We didn't. He was apprehended by the vigilante.
然後聯繫了蘭斯警官
Who then contacted officer Lance.
局長  我可以解釋...
Lieutenant, I can explain--
不  我想我很清楚是怎麼回事
No, I think I got a pretty clear picture.
天啊  你可真不是一般的笨
God, you're a special kind of stupid.
你不戴警徽而穿那套制服的
The whole reason you're wearing that uniform
唯一原因
instead of a detective's shield
是因為你跟治安維持者同流合污了
is 'cause you were working with the vigilante.
一個小女孩失蹤了  你只是
A young girl is missing, and you just--
現在你就因為他一聲令下而逮捕了某人嗎
And now you arrest someone on his say-so?
如果你下一個穿的制服
You'll be lucky if the next uniform
不是囚服  你就慶幸吧
that puts you in isn't prison gray.
他們都叫你喪鐘
They're calling you Deathstroke.
有點兒太高調了
It's a bit flamboyant.
我很喜歡
I like it.
你怎麼從島上逃出來的
How did you get off the island?
這就是你問我的第一個問題嗎
That is your first question?
你已經表明
Well, you've made it pretty clear
絕對不會告訴我妹妹的下落
that you're not going to tell me where my sister is,
所以沒錯  這是我問你的第一個問題
so, yeah. That's my first question.
我遊出來的
I swam.
但那也是經歷了千辛萬苦的
But it wasn't without its obstacles.
激流想把我淹沒
The rip current dragged me under.
暗礁上的石頭讓我皮開肉綻
The rocks on the reef cut up my flesh to the bone.
但是米拉庫魯
But the Mirakuru...
讓一切都再生了
It regenerated everything.
除了這隻眼
Except this.
這房間裡只有我們兩個人
You know, it's just the two of us in here,
所以你說實話吧
so why don't we try being honest?
你為什麼要這麼做
Why are you doing this?
你知道為什麼
You know why.
那是五年前的事了
It was five years ago.
猶如昨天
It was yesterday.
我試著想放開島上的事
Oh, I tried to let go of the island...
但記憶依舊纏著我
but it's still got a hold on me.
如果你每晚都穿的兜帽是某種象徵的話
And if that hood that you wear every night is any indication,
記憶也還纏著你啊  孩子
it's still got a hold of you, kid.
她對你什麼都沒做  是我做的
She never did anything to you. I did.
莎朵是因為我所做的選擇而死
Shado is dead because of a choice that I made.
所以懲罰我  責怪我
So punish me. Blame me.
但是
But...
西婭
Thea.
你想讓我求你嗎
You want me to beg?
這就是你的目的嗎  讓我求你
Is that what this all about? Because I'm begging.
你贏了
You win.
求你了
Just, please...
請告訴我她在哪兒
Please tell me where she is.
你能這樣說一定很不容易
Hmm, that must have been hard for you to say.
西婭
Thea...
西婭在...
Well, Thea's--
奎恩先生
Mr. Queen.
誰讓你進來的
Who the hell let you in here?
威爾遜先生
Mr. Wilson...
你可以走了
you are free to go,
警局深深地向你道歉
with the department's deepest apologies.
不用  警督
There's no need, lieutenant.
一名無辜的女孩生死未卜
An innocent girl's life hangs in the balance.
你需要追查一切有希望的線索
You need to follow every lead possible.
但你還是應該知道蘭斯警官
Well, still, you should know that Officer Lance
會面對很嚴重的罪行指控
is facing some very serious charges.
別以我的名義起訴他們
Well, don't pursue them on my behalf.
我可不是會記仇的人
I'm not one to hold a grudge.
威爾遜先生  威爾遜先生
Mr. Wilson, Mr. Wilson,
警方已經撤銷對你的所有指控了嗎
have the police cleared you of all charges?
我當時在哥斯達黎加  但一聽到這個噩耗
I was in Costa Rica, but returned to Starling City
就立刻回到了星城
as soon as I heard the terrible news.
關於奎恩的失蹤  你是怎麼跟他們說的
What did you tell them about Thea Queen's disappearance?
我向他們提供了我所能支配的一切資源
I'm offering every resource at my disposal,
再加上五百萬美元懸賞
plus a $5 million reward
以求任何關於綁架西婭•奎恩的人的信息
for any information that leads to Thea Queen's captors.
我是狄格  我正跟著他
This is Dig, I've got the follow.
在他車上安的追蹤器運轉正常
Tracker on his car is active.
羅伊  他正往你那邊走去
Roy, he's coming up on your position.
看到他了  他拐入了沃納街
Got him. He's turning up Warner.
看到了  正往北方走
I see him. Heading north.
該死  我跟丟了
Damn it, I lost him!
沒事  我還跟著他
It's all right. I still have eyes on him.
莎拉  右轉去唐尼街
Sara, cut right onto Downey.
明白
Got 'em.
不是  不是  不是他的車
Negative. Negative, it's not him!
什麼
What?!
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
他克隆了追蹤器的信號
He's cloned the tracker's signal.
羅伊  你得趕快移動
Roy, you've got to move!
羅伊  你得在福勒街上追蹤到他
Roy, you got to pick him up on Fuller.
羅伊  你還跟著他嗎
Roy, do you still have eyes on him?
羅伊
Roy?
Roy!
出去
Leave us.
對不起我離開了這麼久
Sorry I was gone for so long.
去死吧
Screw you.
我看見奧利弗和你母親了
I saw Oliver and your mother.
他們都非常擔心你
They're all quite worried about you.
如果你敢傷害他們  我發誓我要...
If you hurt them, I swear I--
請繼續說
Please. Go on.
把那句子說完
Finish that sentence.
我很好奇一個十九歲的女孩
I'm curious to know what kind of threat
能做出什麼樣的威脅
a 19-year-old girl can make.
你想要我怎麼樣
What do you want with me?
這個嘛  西婭
Well, that, Thea...
說來話長
is a very long story.
看來我有的是時間
Looks like I've got time.
並沒有
Not at all.
你可以走了
You're free to go.
什麼
What?
我要表明一個觀點
I had to make a point,
我表明了
and I made it.
門沒鎖
The door is unlocked,
你什麼時候想離開都可以
so you can leave any time you'd like.
但那些為你工作的人
But those guys who work for you
我一走出去就會朝我開槍
will shoot me the second I walk out.
他們不會的
No, they won't.
他們的任務只是在我回來之前看住你
Their instructions were to keep you here until I returned.
現在我已經回來了  所以
And I have. So...
你可以離開了
you're free to go.
但一旦你走了
But, if you do,
就永遠不會知道你哥哥的秘密了
you may never know about your brother's secret.
什麼
What?
你哥哥有一個秘密  西婭
Your brother has a secret, Thea.
想知道是什麼嗎
Would you like to know what it is?
所以
So...
現在該怎麼做
what now?
等奧利弗
Wait for Oliver.
想想下一步該怎麼做
Figure out what our next move will be.
你是說等他的命令吧
Wait for him to tell us, you mean.
沒有奎恩國王的聖旨我們什麼也不能做
We can't do anything without King Queen's permission.
你話說過頭了  羅伊
You're out of line, Roy.
好了  大家都冷靜一下
All right, let's all just calm down here.
斯萊德暫占上風  這是兵家常事
Slade outplayed us. It happens.
不  都怪員警放走了斯萊德
No, it only happened because the police let Slade go--
而那是奧利弗叫我們把他送進去的
after we turned him in, because Oliver told us to.
不然我們該怎麼做呢
What were we supposed to do?
你是特種部隊的
You're Special Forces.
她是個跨國殺手
She's an international assassin.
憑我們三個
You would think between the three of us,
不把他交給員警
we could have gotten answers
我們也就逼出答案了
out of Slade ourselves instead of turning him into the police.
最噁心的是  他說要這麼做
Here's what's really sick; is we didn't even question him
我們都沒有人質疑是不是應該如此
because he said it was the right thing to do.
就像他說我該和西婭分手
Just like he said that I needed to break up with Thea
而一周之前
one week after telling me
他還告訴我讓西婭一個人不安全
that it wasn't safe for me to leave her alone--
等等
Wait!
難道你覺得斯萊德抓走西婭是奧利弗的錯
You think it's oliver's fault that Slade took Thea?
我認為我沒能阻止斯萊德是他的錯
I think it was his fault that I wasn't there to stop Slade.
我認為你只是因為跟丟了斯萊德而遷怒於他
And I think you're just blaming Oliver because you lost Slade.
你們正搞在一起  你當然幫他說話了
Well, of course you'd take his side, you're screwing him.
能讓我們單獨待一會嗎
Can you guys give us a minute, please?
你記不記得她多愛畫畫
Do you remember how she loved to color?
你爸爸一箱一箱地給她買蠟筆
Your father would buy her boxes of crayons by the truckload.
卻總是滿足不了她
She could never get enough.
她老在牆上畫畫
She'd draw on the walls.
我卻總生不起氣來  因為她如此可愛
And I could never get angry, because it was just so adorable.
你應該去休息一下
You should try to get some sleep.
我的寶貝還活著嗎
Is my baby still alive?
什麼
What?
我的寶貝還活著嗎
Is my baby still alive?
是的
Yes.
我忍受了喪子之痛整整五年
I woke up every day for five years the mother who lost her son.
我不能
I-- I can't...
我不能再承受一次了
I can't endure it again.
現在你對我恨之入骨
And now you hate me,
而且並非是無理取鬧
and you have every justification.
-現在不合適  -就是現在
- Now is not the time. - Yes, it is.
這是最好的時機
It is exactly the time.
我告訴過你那些欺騙
I've told you that these lies
是為了保護家人
were to keep our family safe;
讓我們團結
to keep us all together,
但那就是最大的謊言
but that was the biggest lie of all.
我用它欺騙了你  西婭
And I told it to you, to Thea,
和我自己
to myself.
因為我太脆弱
Because I was too weak
不能面對真相
to face any kind of truth.
現在發生的事不是你的錯
What's happening now isn't your fault.
從子女出生起
From the moment your children are born,
你就擔心世界會不會傷害他們
you worry what the world might do to them.
但你最擔心的是自己會不會傷害他們
But you never stop to think what you might do to them.
我們可能就是自己最大的敵人
That we could be our own worst enemy.
奧利
Ollie!
你對他做了什麼
What did you do to him?
不足掛齒
Not enough.
你又對他做了什麼
And what did you do to him?
我們把他打暈了  這樣比較方便
We just knocked him. It's better that way.
他不太贊成這場交易
He wasn't exactly a fan of the arrangement.
可想而知
I would imagine.
亨德里克是你的了
Hendrik's all yours.
我知道
I know.
等等
Wait.
米拉庫魯真個很神奇的東西
It's an incredible thing, this Mirakuru.
它不僅給了我力量
Not only does it give you strength,
還強化了我的感官
it also heightens all of your senses.
炸藥有一種特殊的味道
TNT has a particular smell.
還有多久爆炸
How long before it goes off?
90秒
90 seconds?
還是60秒
60 seconds?
你們可能以為爆炸能殺死我
You're probably thinking that the blast would kill me,
我可不這麼認為
but I disagree.
不過你們就不一樣了
Not that I could say the same for you lot.
我迫不及待
I am tempted
想看到你被炸成碎片
to see this blow you to pieces.
不過話說回來  也許我可以直接殺死你
But then again, maybe I'll just shoot you
就像他殺死莎朵一樣
the same way that he shot Shado.
不
No.
斯萊德
Slade...
你要去哪裡
Hey, where are you going?
乾坐在這裡可幫不了西婭  不是嗎
Well, sitting around here isn't helping Thea, now is it?
你這樣魯莽行事是不行的 羅伊
Neither is you running off half-cocked, Roy.
我知道你們認為
I know that you think
是米拉庫魯在影響我  但並非如此
that this is the Mirakuru, but it's not.
我是對的  你也清楚
I'm right, and you know that I am.
所以你最好別他媽擋著我
So you better get the hell out of my way.
羅伊  冷靜點
Roy, just calm down.
西婭也會希望我們這麼做的
It's what Thea would want us to do.
她說的對  羅伊  我們先按兵不動
She's right, Roy. Come on, let's throttle back.
下一箭會直穿你的心臟
Next one goes into your chest.
放開他
Let him go.
你真的要因為
You would honestly kill me because I dare
我批評全能的奧利弗•奎恩而殺我嗎
to criticize the almighty Oliver Queen?
不  我殺你是因為你正在傷害我的朋友
No, I'd kill you because you're hurting my friend.
放開他
Let him go.
Let him go!
這下面到底怎麼回事
What the hell's going on down here?
我不幹了
I'm done.
就這麼回事
That's what's going on.
西婭在外頭受傷了或是更糟  因為一個人
Thea, she's out there, hurt or worse, because of one person.
而那個人不是斯萊德•威爾遜
And that is not Slade Wilson.
羅伊
Roy...
我曾那麼信任你
I believed in you.
我已經沒有理由留下了
There's nothing left for me here.
-我的天  奧利弗  -又怎麼了
- Oh, my god. Oliver... - Now what?
宣傳部起草了一份很有力的聲明
Publicity has drafted a rather compelling statement,
我會去參加脫口秀來引導輿論導向
and I will be doing the talk show rounds to control the spin.
我很抱歉  羅切夫女士  但他很
I'm sorry, Ms. Rochev, but he was very...
急迫
insistent.
你們先出去吧
Can you give us the room, please?
伊莎貝爾  你幹了什麼
Isabel, what have you done?
我嗎  沒做什麼
Me? Very little.
你讓我當上總裁之時
You're the one who made this possible
就讓這一切有了可能
when you made me CEO.
我知道只是暫時的
I know it was only temporary,
但給了我所需要的權限
but it gave me the authority I needed
來召集緊急董事會
to call an emergency board meeting.
就在半小時前
As of 30 minutes ago,
你的公司歸我了
your company belongs to me.
董事們一致同意將我的任命變成永久性的
The directors unanimously made my appointment permanent.
我本來想說他們對你的領導力失去了信任
I'd say they lost faith in your leadership,
不過那樣聽起來就好像你有領導力似的
but that would imply there was any.
也許你應該少花點精力在你的
Maybe you should have focused a little less on your...
晚間活動上
evening activities.
斯萊德
Slade...
你為他工作
You're working for him.
和他工作
With.
他知道把我安插進你的家族企業
He knew planting me in your family's business
會把你拉回星城
would draw you back to Starling City.
說實話  我很懷疑  但是
Truth be told, I was skeptical, but...
為什麼你要這麼做
Why are you doing this?!
你不知道還真是可悲
I think it's sad you don't know.
父債子還
The sins of the father are the sins of the son.
快告訴我  我妹妹在哪裡
You are going to tell me where my sister is,
否則我就殺了你
or I am going to kill you.
她在哪兒
Where is she?!
他把她關在一個貨站裡
He's holding her at a storage depot
就在市區邊上  托斯卡貨運
just outside the city limits. Tosca Cartage.
我怎麼知道你不是在騙我
How do I know you're not lying?!
你真可愛  你還不知道吧
It's cute how you think this isn't all playing out
事情進展正像他所希望的那樣
exactly how he wants it to.
而且他希望你一個人去
And he wants you to come alone.
如果他嗅到了你搭檔的氣息
If he even smells your partners,
他會把小西婭像條鮭魚一樣開膛破肚
he will gut sweet little Thea like a trout.
跟你共事很愉快  奧利弗
It was a pleasure doing business with you, Oliver.
至少讓我們包圍周邊地區
At least let us surround the perimeter.
不  伊莎貝爾說的很明白
No, Isabel was very clear.
我一個人去  否則西婭性命難保
I come alone or Thea dies.
奧利  這是斯萊德的又一個遊戲  除非
Ollie, this is another one of Slade's games, and unless--
不  我什麼都做不了  莎拉
No, what I can't do, Sara, is nothing!
如果是勞蕾爾你會怎麼做
What would you do if it were Laurel,
如果是你的父親或者母親呢
or your father, or your mother?
我不想一次又一次陷入同樣的爭論之中
I will not get dragged into the same debate over and over again!
去吧
Go.
去找到西婭
Go get Thea.
阻止斯萊德
Stop Slade.
做你該做的
Do whatever it takes.
徹底解決問題
End this once and for all.
停車  停車
Stop, stop!
萬聖節已經過去半年了  傻帽
Halloween was six months ago, ass hat.
滾開  不然就放到你  聽到了嗎
Now get off the road or get put down. You hear me?
我有個提議給你們
I have a proposal for you men.
-說  -奧利弗  你沒事吧
- Go! - Oliver, are you ok?
我沒事  但西婭不在這裡
Yeah, I'm fine, but Thea's not here.
-你做到了  -做到什麼了
- You did it. - Did what?
西婭沒事  她沒事
Thea's fine. She's fine.
她五分鐘前走進了分局
She walked into the precinct five minutes ago.
安然無恙
Safe and sound.
奧利弗  你聽到了嗎
Oliver, did you hear me?
-西婭呢  -她沒事  沒受傷
- Thea? - She's fine, no injuries.
-他沒碰她  -他不在那裡
- He didn't touch her. - He wasn't there.
-他手下很多雇傭兵  -他不在那裡
- He had a lot of men, hired guns. - He wasn't there.
因為他正在別處忙活
Because he was busy elsewhere.
鐵山監獄重新啟用了一個地震中毀掉的區
Iron Heights reopened a wing damaged in the quake.
有一輛運囚車被斯萊德劫持了
There was a prisoner transfer. Slade hijacked it.
為他的軍隊招募士兵
Soldiers for his army.
綁架西婭只是為了分散注意力
Abducting Thea was all a diversion.
奧利弗
Oliver!
謝天謝地
Oh, thank god.
我的寶貝
Oh, my baby!
Ohh! My baby.
怎麼了
What?
他告訴我了
He told me.
威爾遜先生
Mr. Wilson...
他把你的秘密告訴我了
He told me your secret.
這些年你是怎麼騙我的
How you've been lying to me for years.
你怎能不告訴我  馬爾科姆•梅林是我父親
How could you not tell me Malcolm Merlyn was my father?!
我那麼信任你
I believed in you.
我們是想保證你的安全
We were trying to keep you safe.
你知道你這樣聽起來像誰嗎
Do you have any idea who you sound like?
聽起來像她
You sound like her.
斯萊德
Slade...
死亡太便宜他們了
Death's too good for them.
這個島就是對他們的懲罰
This island should be their punishment.
死亡太便宜你們了
Death is too good for you.
這個島就是對你們的懲罰
This island should be your punishment.
是他們餘生的牢籠
Their prison for the rest of their days.
是你們餘生的牢籠
Your prison for the rest of your days.
帶他走
Get him out of here.
斯萊德
Slade...
回去
Get back!
我可以幫你
I can help you.
是生  是死
You can live, or you can die.
你自己選
You choose.
你想給自己的家人捎點消息嗎
Would you like to send a message to your family?
船修好之後我就去拜訪他們
'Cause as soon as this boat is fixed, I'm paying them a visit.
星城地界  您已出城
漫長的一夜啊
Hell of a night.
昆汀•蘭斯  說話真委婉啊
Quentin Lance, master of the understatement.
借一步說話  警官
A word, officer?
稍等  親愛的
Hold on, sweetheart.
怎麼了
Yeah?
我已經跟斯賓塞地檢官說過你的情況了
I've spoken to DA Spencer about your...situation.
她不想起訴...
She doesn't want to press charges--
前提是你合作
if you cooperate.
告訴我們治安維持者在哪裡
Tell us where the vigilante is.
我也想告訴你們  可我不知道
Well, I'd love to, but I don't know.
那就太不幸了
Well, that's unfortunate.
看樣子是的
Yeah, it looks like.
昆汀•拉裡•蘭斯  你因為
Quentin Larry Lance, you're under arrest
參與謀劃幫助罪犯等多項罪名被捕
for conspiracy and aiding in multiple felonies.
搞什麼  你瘋了嗎
What? Are you out of your mind?!
你幹什麼呢  威爾遜  是威爾遜幹的
What are you doing? Wilson--Wilson did it!
我抓對人了  你...
I collared the right guy. What are you--
你有權保持沉默
You have the right to remain silent.
你這是幹什麼
What are you doing?
-你有權找律師協助  -爸爸
- You have the right to an attorney. - Dad!
雖然有專家稱這是大打同情牌
Riding what pundits are calling a sympathy bump,
但是莫伊拉•奎恩在昨天
Moira Queen pulled far ahead of Sebastian Blood
剛進行的投票中  遠遠領先
in the latest polls conducted in
塞巴斯蒂安•布拉德...
the last 24 hours by channel--
竟然就這樣搞砸了
The whole thing just blew up in my face!
這讓我還怎麼當選
How the hell do I get elected now?!
你是不是該換種語氣跟我說話
I think you intended a different tone.
你說過我會成為市長的
You said I'd be mayor!
你就這樣把成果拱手讓給
And you just delivered this election
莫伊拉•奎恩了  為什麼
for Moira Queen, and for what?
你跟奎恩家族的人到底有什麼關係
What is this obsession you have with the Queen family?
你沒跟他說嗎
You haven't told him?
你答應過我的
You promised me.
我說過會把星城給你
I promised you this city.
我還說過給你一支軍隊讓你奪取星城
I promised you an army with which to take it.
現在什麼情況
What is our status?
奎恩聯合企業的應用科學部門
Queen Consolidated's applied sciences division
正在全力
is now fully dedicated to
用你的血樣復制血清
replicating a serum based on your blood sample.
看到了吧
You see...
一切皆在掌握之中
Everything is proceeding as planned.
你要去哪裡
Where are you going now?
去處理一下我的目標
To service my obsession.
得再讓奧利弗•奎恩分分神
Oliver Queen needs one more distraction.
你們兩個在這裡幹什麼
What are you two doing here?
我們想著你會來這裡
We thought this is where you would go.
這個不難猜  你最近一直
You're predictable. That, and you've been
都在這裡的小床上過夜
sleeping on the cot at night.
你們到底想幹什麼
What are you doing here?
要不我們去哪裡
Where else would we be?
羅伊是對的
Roy was right.
每次轉折點上  我都會作出錯誤的決定
At every turn, I had made the wrong decision.
對他
With him,
對公司  還有...
with...the company, and...
對西婭
and with Thea.
我太專注於斯萊德對我的所作所為
I was so focused on what Slade might do to me,
以至於我...
that it never...
從沒想過自己會對自己作出什麼事
even occurred to me what I could do to myself.
我才是自己最大的敵人
I am my own worst enemy.
那是斯萊德說的  奧利弗  不要輕信他的話
That's Slade talking, Oliver. Don't let him in your head.
他在我的腦海中揮之不去  狄格爾
I can't keep him out of my head, Diggle!
我...  我什麼事都阻止不了他
I can't...I can't stop him from doing anything.
你可以的
Yes, you can.
你憑什麼這麼確定
What makes you so sure?
因為有我們在
Because you're not alone, man.
現在幹什麼  老大
Now what, boss?
現在我們反擊
Now we fight back.
警方簽發了針對斯萊德•威爾遜的拘捕令
Police have issued a warrant for Slade Wilson
因為西婭•奎恩指證
after Thea Queen named him
他是綁架她的幕後黑手
as the mastermind of her kidnapping yesterday.
這是奎恩小姐被釋放  而威爾遜被捕
This in the wake of Wilson's arrest and subsequent release
然後又被星城警方釋放後幾個小時後的情況
by the SCPD hours before Ms. Queen was released.
在向媒體的聲明中
In a statement to the press,
星城警署局長富蘭克林•派克
SCPD lieutenant Franklin Pike
重申了自己對警局方面的支持
reiterated his support for his department
雖然這件事顯而易見是警方烏龍了
despite what appears to be a serious blunder.
他還說  星城警署有責任...
He went on to say, the SCPD is committed--
確保對任何人的逮捕都符合法律規定
to making sure any arrest they make is a legal one,
但是沒有充分證據...
but without sufficient--
不用害怕
Don't worry.
我不是來傷害你的
I am not here to harm you.
去死吧
Go to hell!
人終有一死
All in good time, I'm sure.
但是我死前
But before then,
我要來星城
I have come to Starling City
看到奧利弗•奎恩痛苦
to see Oliver Queen suffer.
奧利弗...  什麼
Oliver...what?
為什麼
Why?
因為你根本不知道他的真面目
Because he's not the man you think he is.
你怎麼知道
And how would you know that?
因為我知道奧利弗•奎恩就是...
Because I know Oliver Queen is...
綠箭俠
The Arrow.